{
    "id": "b83b080f4a6f49caa769cdf3ed7bbd5a",
    "title": "Comparative Expressions Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "39e6226e903b49b8adc7cc88db374cd5",
            "title": "Comparative Expressions Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "We have got ………………………… expensive clothes for the fuller figure.",
                    "description": "Less is the comparative form of little.",
                    "answers": [
                        "little",
                        "less",
                        "lesser"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are going …………………………….",
                    "description": "We use double comparatives to indicate that something is changing.",
                    "answers": [
                        "more slowly and more slowly",
                        "slowlier and slowlier",
                        "more and more slowly"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………………. now own a car.",
                    "description": "We use double comparatives to indicate that something is changing.",
                    "answers": [
                        "More families and more families",
                        "More and more families",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You are getting ………………………………",
                    "description": "We use double comparatives to indicate that something is changing.",
                    "answers": [
                        "fatter and fatter",
                        "more fat and more fat",
                        "more and more fat"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The more he works, …………………………",
                    "description": "In this construction, the word order in both clauses is ‘the + comparative + subject + verb’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "he earns the less",
                        "the less he earns",
                        "the lesser he earns"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The population of China is ………………………….",
                    "description": "The population of China cannot be greater than India. It can only be greater than the population of India. We add the expression ‘that of’ to express that idea.",
                    "answers": [
                        "greater than India",
                        "greater than that of India",
                        "greater than of India"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is …………………………. person ever to climb Mt. Everest?",
                    "description": "We use the before the superlative.",
                    "answers": [
                        "the young",
                        "youngest",
                        "the younger",
                        "the youngest"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is the brightest student ………………………… the class.",
                    "description": "After superlatives we use ‘in’ with a singular noun referring to a place or group.",
                    "answers": [
                        "in",
                        "of",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She was the nicest person ………………………………… them all.",
                    "description": "After superlatives, of can be used before plurals.",
                    "answers": [
                        "in",
                        "of",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She earns more than …………………………….",
                    "description": "Object pronouns are more common after than. Subject pronouns can also be used with verbs.",
                    "answers": [
                        "me",
                        "I do",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She looks ………………………. than her daughter.",
                    "description": "We can use the adverb'no' to modify comparatives. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "less older",
                        "not older",
                        "no older"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "This restaurant is ………………………… than that restaurant.",
                    "description": "The expression 'a little' can be used to modify comparatives. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "little expensive",
                        "little less expensive",
                        "a little less expensive"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}